Richard M. Williams

310.350.1385 • Torrance, CA 90504 • williamsitv@yahoo.com • www.linkedin.com/in/richmwilliams

• https://rwilliam4444.github.io/ • https://rwilliam4444.github.io/Projects/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

IT professional with 8 years of supervisory experience, over 20 years of windows server administration experience & 6 years of software development\automation experience. Leadership: Oversaw 6 employees at TRW and was a Team Lead for 50 plus windows Administrators at IBM on the Disney Account. Planned, designed, built and managed Windows platform servers in an enterprise environment. 6 years working with automation tools, resulting in minimizing SA labor hours & reducing human errors on windows related tasks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM - work from home

2006 - Present

Windows System Administrator \ Team Lead \ Software Automation Engineer

- Software Automation Engineer (2014-2020): Designed windows automation on over 100 IBM accounts. Developed work for cleaning disk space, archiving logs, performing CIS tasks, etc.
 Created immediate savings in SA labor hours & dramatically reduced human errors.
- Team Lead (2010-2014): Led team of 50 + System Admins. Championed tasks ranging from directing, scheduling & assigning project work. Also, trained new hires, created & published team room documents, backed up Manager, & supervised, coached & counseled staff as needed.
- System Administrator (2006-2010): Spearheaded a wide range of activities for over 3000 Walt Disney windows servers (i.e. tool deployments, patching, HBA upgrades, server builds, etc...).

Walt Disney - Burbank, CA

1998 - 2006

Senior Systems Administrator - BVHE Division

- Configured, installed, and controlled over 60 windows servers.
- Oversaw operation and maintenance of applicable servers & delivered technical assistance in identifying, evaluating & implementing new systems.
- Monitored & maintained hardware, operating systems, & software for 60 plus servers.
 Interacted with various vendors in order to resolve outstanding issues.
- Conducted remote support for over 50 field sales users. Facilitated technical tasks on their laptops, DSL\CABLE modems, routers, firewalls, blackberry phones, printers & network switches. Planned, coordinated & scheduled various maintenance & upgrade activities as needed.

Richard M. Williams 310.350.1385

• Streamlined 1st, 2nd & 3rd level support to Disney's site-level personnel & organized & tracked laptop loaner equipment.

TRW Systems Federal Credit Union - Redondo Beach, CA

1993 - 1998

Computer Room Supervisor

- Administered, scheduled, trained, & motivated 6 employees. Performed daily processing requirements as established by the Data Processing Mgr.
- Collaborated with offsite programmers \ engineers in order to resolve software & hardware problems and also coordinated repairs & maintenance on office supplies and equipment.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts - Bus Admin w\ emphasis in CIS - Loyola Marymount University, Westchester, CA. Graduated - June 1997

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Microsoft Certified IT Professional: sys admin (Retired) self study 2012 MCP ID 981686
- CompTIA Cloud Essentials Professional (Retired) self study 2012 Candidate ID sr5059930
- w2k8 AD configuration & network configuration (Retired) self study 2012 MCP ID 981686
- VMware Certified Professional on vsphere 4 (Retired) self study course in 2010 VCP086781
- MCSA 2003 \ MCSA 2003 Plus MESSAGING (Retired) self study course in 2009 MCP ID 981686
- A+ Hardware Technician Certification (Retired) self study 1998 Verification # is CBODTT5268
- MCSE Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (Retired) self study course in 1998

AWARDS AND HONORS

Thank you Awards - IBM 2006 - Present

Acquired over 10 "Thanks Awards" at IBM for work above & beyond what was expected.

Go Big or Go Home Award - Disney 2002

- Acknowledged for outstanding achievement award by Disney's BVHE Sales Management team.
- Obtained spot bonus award from Disney's I.T. management team for outstanding achievement.

Beta Gamma Sigma - Loyola Marymount University 1996

Accepted into Beta Gamma Sigma - GPA in top 5% of Business Administration class.